<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Saqib&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>https://saqibmir1.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Saqib&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 19:32:22 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saqibmir1.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Concepts vs Tools</title>
      <link>https://saqibmir1.github.io/posts/concepts-vs-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 19:32:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saqibmir1.github.io/posts/concepts-vs-tools/</guid>
      <description>Most people learn tools instead of leraning concepts first. As a consaquence, they often lack the funcamental knowledge of how things actually work
Introduction Like for example, many CS students use VS Code with mulitiple extensions for compiling and running code, which i&amp;rsquo;m not saying is necessarily a bad thing but here is the issue; most of these people don&amp;rsquo;t even know how to manually compile their code manually or use a terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paradox of Choice</title>
      <link>https://saqibmir1.github.io/posts/paradox-of-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 19:32:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saqibmir1.github.io/posts/paradox-of-choice/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Paradox of choice - why more is less is a book by american psychologist Barry Schawtz where he argues that eliminating consumers choices can greatly reduce indecisiveness and stress for shoppers. The linux community is vast, with numerous options (distros) to choose from, whichy leads to the paradox of choice. When faced with too many choices, new linux users tend to make either bad desicions or make fine desicions and feel disappointed about the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Elitism</title>
      <link>https://saqibmir1.github.io/posts/linux-elitism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 19:32:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saqibmir1.github.io/posts/linux-elitism/</guid>
      <description>Under Construction </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Recommenation</title>
      <link>https://saqibmir1.github.io/posts/software-recommenation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 19:32:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saqibmir1.github.io/posts/software-recommenation/</guid>
      <description>Under Construction </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto Arch</title>
      <link>https://saqibmir1.github.io/posts/auto-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 19:31:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saqibmir1.github.io/posts/auto-arch/</guid>
      <description>Auto Arch is a shell script i made to install a fully functional arch system including all the software i use
Introduction Just a few bash scripts to install Arch Linux, a desktop environment, all the software i use, and some tweaks.
How to use Run these commands on the initial prompt:
git clone https://github.com/saqibmir1 cd auto-arch ./install How it works There are five scripts in total: install.sh, which installs the base arch; chroot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Roms</title>
      <link>https://saqibmir1.github.io/posts/custom-roms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 19:32:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saqibmir1.github.io/posts/custom-roms/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a to-the-point, no bullshit guide on why and how to install custom rom on any andorid device.
What is custom rom Andorid is an open source project and every andorid smartphone company uses their own skin/ui for their phones, for example redmi uses miui, samsung uses one ui and so on to make them look diffent from their competetors. These roms are calles stock roms.
So custom is is essentially a custom skin or custom ui built and maintained by developers voluntarily.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
